Guide to the International Brotherhood of Boilermakers, Iron Shipbuilders, Blacksmiths, Forgers, and Helpers of America, Local 104 (Seattle, Washington) records
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
International Brotherhood of Boilermakers, Iron Shipbuilders, Blacksmiths, Forgers, and Helpers of America, Local 104 (Seattle, Washington) records
1937-1961
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
1409
1409-001
International Brotherhood of Boilermakers, Iron Shipbuilders, Blacksmiths, Forgers, and Helpers of America.$bLocal 104 (Seattle, Wash.)
7 cubic feet 7 boxes
Records of a Seattle, Washington, labor organization.
Labor organization, Seattle, Washington. Prior to July 1953 the organization's name was the International Brotherhood of Boiler Makers, Iron Ship Builders, and Helpers of America, Local 104 (Seattle).
Arranged in three series:
Jurisdictional Materials, circa 1937-1961
Disputes, undated
Subject Files, circa 1937-1959
Contains correspondence, subject files, agreements, and other material of the International Brotherhood of Boilermakers, Iron Shipbuilders, Blacksmiths, Forgers, and Helpers of America, Local 104 (Seattle), and the organization that preceded it, the International Brotherhood of Boiler Makers, Iron Ship Builders, and Helpers of America, Local 104 (Seattle). Records document labor relations, union activities, and industry issues.
The records are open to all users.
Gift of the International Brotherhood of Boilermakers, Iron Shipbuilders, Blacksmiths, Forgers, and Helpers of America, Local 104, via James O'Brien, August 1970.
The University of Washington Libraries also holds microfilm of issues of the newspapers, the 104 Reporter (published 1942-1947) and the Seattle Boilermakers' 104 Reporter (after 1947), which both were published by the International Brotherhood of Boiler Makers, Iron Ship Builders, and Helpers of America, Local 104.
International Brotherhood of Boilermakers, Iron Shipbuilders, Blacksmiths, Forgers, and Helpers of America.$bLocal 104 (Seattle, Wash.)$vArchives; International Brotherhood of Boiler Makers, Iron Ship Builders, and Helpers of America.$bLocal 104 (Seattle, Wash.)$vArchives; International Brotherhood of Boiler Makers, Iron Ship Builders, and Helpers of America.$bLocal 104 (Seattle, Wash.); Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); Shipbuilding industry$xEmployees$xLabor unions$zWashington (State)$zSeattle; Shipbuilding industry$zWashington (State); Collective labor agreements$zWashington (State); Collective labor agreements$xMetal industry; Metal-workers$zWashington (State); Metal-workers$xLabor unions$zWashington (State); correspondence
Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor Unions; Labor History; Ships and Shipping; Seattle; Washington (State)
- Jurisdictional Materials, circa 1937-1961
  - PipeFitters -- Boilermakers, 1937-1954 (Box 1)
  - Pipefitters -- Boilermakers, 1955-1961 (Box 1)
  - Sheet Metal Workers -- Boilermakers, 1946-1960 (Box 1)
  - Sheet Metal -- Boilermaker Agreements, undated (Box 1)
  - Millwrights -- Boilermakers, 1952-1959 (Box 1)
  - Millwrights, Agreements, undated (Box 1)
  - United Association -- Boilermakers, undated (Box 1)
  - Pipe Fabrication, undated (Box 1)
  - Ironworkers -- Boiler Makers Agreements, undated (Box 1)
  - Iron Workers, Boilermakers, 1954-1961 (Box 1)
- Disputes Handled by Building and Construction Trades Unit, undated (Box 1)
- Subject Files, circa 1937-1959
  Arranged in rough alphabetical order.
  - McNary Dam, undated (Box 1)
  - Mann, Frank -- National Labor Relations Board Case, undated (Box 1)
  - Manson Construction and Engineering, undated (Box 1)
  - Manson -- Osberg, Alaska, undated (Box 1)
  - Jurisdiction Agreement -- Machinists, undated (Box 1)
  - Markey Machine, undated (Box 1)
  - Membership Reports to Grand Lodge, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Maritime Shipyard, undated (Box 2)
  - Merger, undated (Box 2)
  - MIS Company, undated (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence -- Field, undated (Box 2)
  - Membership Correspondence, undated (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence and Agreements -- Independent, undated (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Shops, undated (Box 2)
  - Morgan Electric, undated (Box 2)
  - Morrison -- Knudson, undated (Box 2)
  - National Labor Relations Board, undated (Box 2)
  - National Labor Relations Board -- Compliance, undated (Box 2)
  - Nicholson Manufacturing Company, 1956 (Box 2)
  - National Steel Construction, undated (Box 2)
  - Nonpartisan Political League, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Nordline Manufacturing Co., 1957 (Box 2)
  - National Labor Relations Board, undated (Box 2)
  - Northwest Metal Products, undated (Box 2)
  - Northwest Shipyard, undated (Box 2)
  - Northwest Tractor and Equipment, undated (Box 2)
  - Pacific Car -- Everett, Washington, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Pacific Car and Foundry, Everett Division, undated (Box 2)
  - Pacific Car and Foundry, Everett, Washington, 1953 (Box 2)
  - Pacific Car and Foundry, Everett, Washington, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Pacific Coast Metal Grades, undated (Box 2)
  - Pacific Coast Marine District Council, undated (Box 3)
  - Pacific Coast Shipyard Negotiating Conference, Proceeding, undated (Box 3)
  - Patternmakers, undated (Box 3)
  - Pacific Northwest Independent, undated (Box 3)
  - Patton, 1958 (Box 3)
  - W.E. Pearson Co., undated (Box 3)
  - Pennstocks, undated (Box 3)
  - Pension, undated (Box 3)
  - J.W. Perron -- Fairbanks, Alaska, undated (Box 3)
  - J.W. Perron, undated (Box 3)
  - Pittsburgh -- Des Moines, 1956 (Box 3)
  - Pittsburgh -- Des Moines Steel Co., undated (Box 3)
  - Pointer Willamette #1, undated (Box 3)
  - Pointer Willamette Agreements, undated (Box 3)
  - Pointer Willamette #2, undated (Box 3)
  - Plant Maintenance -- Anacortes, undated (Box 3)
  - Pointer Willamette National Labor Relations Board, undated (Box 3)
  - Puget Sound Bridge and Dredging Company Correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 3)
  - Pointer -- Willamette (Farr and Angle Case), undated (Box 3)
  - Portland Erection, undated (Box 3)
  - Port of Seattle, Washington, undated (Box 3)
  - Plant Maintenance, Inc., 1957 (Box 3)
  - Prosser Welding Works Agreements -- Correspondence, undated (Box 3)
  - Protective Equipment -- State of Washington, undated (Box 3)
  - P.S.B. & D. Safety, Signed Statement, undated (Box 3)
  - Puget Sound Drake, undated (Box 4)
  - Puget Sound Bridge and Dredge, undated (Box 4)
  - Shop Steward Reports, 1955 (Box 4)
  - Puget Sound Bridge and Dredge Company, 1954 (Box 4)
  - Puget Sound Fabricators, 1957 (Box 4)
  - Raber and Kief, undated (Box 4)
  - Refinery Organization, undated (Box 4)
  - Reliable Welding, undated (Box 4)
  - Renton Central Labor Council, undated (Box 4)
  - Renton School District # 403, undated (Box 4)
  - Renton Machine and Welding Company, undated (Box 4)
  - Republic Steel, undated (Box 4)
  - Right to Work Law, undated (Box 4)
  - Riley Stoker Corporation, undated (Box 4)
  - Robinson Machine, undated (Box 4)
  - Rothschild International Stevedoring Company, undated (Box 4)
  - Rowe Machine, undated (Box 4)
  - Renton Boilerworks, undated (Box 4)
  - Ryan-Haworth Shop, undated (Box 4)
  - Safeway Scaffolding Company, undated (Box 4)
  - Sagers, Inc., undated (Box 4)
  - Seattle Boiler Works, undated (Box 4)
  - Seattle Building and Construction Trades Councils, undated (Box 4)
  - Seattle Metal Trades, undated (Box 4)
  - Shop Seniority List, 1958 September (Box 4)
  - Seniority List, 1957 July (Box 4)
  - Seniority List, 1956 (Box 4)
  - Seniority List, 1955 (Box 4)
  - Shell Oil Company -- Paid Bills, 1954 March (Box 4)
  - Shipyard Correspondence, 1950-1958 (Box 4)
  - Shipyard Negotiations and Agreements, 1957-1958 (Box 4)
  - Shipbuilding File, undated (Box 4)
  - Shipyard Miscellany, undated (Box 4)
  - Shipyards, Premium Pay, undated (Box 4)
  - Sitka Mill File, undated (Box 5)
  - Sheet Metal Workers' Addendum, undated (Box 5)
  - Shop Stewards, undated (Box 5)
  - Shop Stewards Meetings, undated (Box 5)
  - Shop Strike, undated (Box 5)
  - Shop Strike, 1951-1952 (Box 5)
  - Sound Industrial Serv. Corp. Maintenance Agreement, undated (Box 5)
  - A.O. Smith, undated (Box 5)
  - Solar Chicago -- Division of U.S. Industries, undated (Box 5)
  - Sparling Sales Limited, undated (Box 5)
  - Steel Construction, undated (Box 5)
  - Stone and Webster, undated (Box 5)
  - Strike Benefits, undated (Box 5)
  - Strike Assessment Fund, 1951 (Box 5)
  - Strike Assessment Excuses, 1953 April 3-1953 May 2 (Box 5)
  - Strike Rolls, undated (Box 5)
  - Sumner Iron Works, undated (Box 5)
  - Swanson Welding Company, undated (Box 5)
  - Taft-Hartley Act -- Bulletins, Letters, undated (Box 5)
  - Tax and Subsistence Rulings, undated (Box 5)
  - Local 541 Taxes and Labor and Industry, undated (Box 5)
  - Local 541 Taxes and Labor and Industry, 1957 and later (Box 5)
  - Temco Company, undated (Box 5)
  - Thomson, P. C., undated (Box 5)
  - J.J. Thorpe N.W. Inc., undated (Box 5)
  - Todds Drydock, 1955 (Box 5)
  - Todds, 1957-1958 (Box 6)
  - Todd Shipyards, Correspondence, etc., 1954 (Box 6)
  - Torrid King, undated (Box 6)
  - Union Labor Reports, 1959 (Box 6)
  - Union Steel Manufacturing, Inc., undated (Box 6)
  - United Concrete Pipe, Moses Lake, Washington, undated (Box 6)
  - United Good Neighbors, undated (Box 6)
  - Unemployment Cases, undated (Box 6)
  - Union Shop Card Receipts, undated (Box 6)
  - Union Tank Works, undated (Box 6)
  - U & I Sugar Co., Contractors, etc., undated (Box 6)
  - U.S.E.S. and Shipyard Cases, undated (Box 6)
  - Valley Iron Works Agreements -- Correspondence, undated (Box 6)
  - Voting Ballots, undated (Box 6)
  - Welders, 1937-1943 (Box 6)
  - Washington Metal Trades, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Washington Metal Trades Correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 6)
  - Wilson Award, undated (Box 6)
  - Welders, 1945-1949 (Box 6)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 6)
  - Welders, 1944 (Box 6)
  - Welding Shop, undated (Box 6)
  - Washington Metal Trades Trust, 1954-1956 (Box 6)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 7)
  - Washington Metal Trades Correspondence, 1945-1948 (Box 7)
  - Washington State Building and Construction Council, circa 1959 (Box 7)
  - Washington State Labor Council, 1957-1959 (Box 7)
  - Washington State Federation of Labor, undated (Box 7)
  - Waitsburg Personal, undated (Box 7)
  - Waitsburg Welding Agreements -- Correspondence, undated (Box 7)
  - Waitsburg Welding Company, undated (Box 7)
  - Ward Cove Builders, undated (Box 7)
  - Waitsburg Welding Works Agreements and Correspondence, undated (Box 7)
  - Waitsburg Confidential, undated (Box 7)
  - Waitsburg Weld, 1947-1948 (Box 7)
  - Washington Iron Works, undated (Box 7)
  - Welders, 1951 (Box 7)
  - Wyatt and Kipper Construction File, undated (Box 7)
  - Weldit Tank and Steel, undated (Box 7)
  - Wells and Wade, undated (Box 7)
  - West Coast Construction, undated (Box 7)
  - Western Blower Company, undated (Box 7)
  - West Street Carriage, undated (Box 7)
  - H.W. Whitaker, undated (Box 7)
  - A. Wilcox Company, undated (Box 7)
  - Wickes Boiler Company, undated (Box 7)
  - Howard S. Wright and Co., undated (Box 7)
  - Wyatt and Kipper, Alaska, undated (Box 7)
  - Wyatt and Kipper Engineers, undated (Box 7)
  - Yakima Building Trades Council, undated (Box 7)
  - Yakima Tank and Steel Agreements, Correspondence, undated (Box 7)
  - Yakima Brazing Agreements, Correspondence, undated (Box 7)
  - Zeeb Iron Works, undated (Box 7)